<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on LETNH - Blog</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on LETNH - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 10:46:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.letnh.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Files in Cloud</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/files-in-cloud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 22:26:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/files-in-cloud/</guid><description>Today we will create a simple web application, where files can be uploaded trough a REST API.
We will have one /upload endpoint which only accepts POST requests, if we then head over to / we will see a list of files uploaded to the server.
This is not for production, please secure appliation and conduct legal advice before putting it in production
Application structure What does the code look like First we define two helper functions to both authenticate agianst azure storage, and create a storage container.</description></item><item><title>Connect on-prem to Azure</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/connect-on-prem-to-azure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 10:46:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/connect-on-prem-to-azure/</guid><description>What is Azure Private Link? Azure Private Link gives the ability to connect Virtual Networks in Azure to either, Azure PaaS services, or other Virtual Networks maintained by &amp;ldquo;customers&amp;rdquo; or other departments.
When using Azure Private Link, it&amp;rsquo;s also possible to connect a network in EU to a network in US to establish a private communication. You are not requiered to setup VPN connections, NAT devices, gateways etc. All traffic sent over the Azure Private Link is kept on Microsoft Global Network.</description></item><item><title>Azure webapps with Container</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/azure-webapps-with-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 19:39:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/azure-webapps-with-container/</guid><description>We are gonna create a simple web application that will utilize FreeGeoIP, to show the user what IP they are using and other infrmationa about it.
We will use Golang with Golang Templates to serve a static site to the user, and then build it into a super small container!
Lets check the code! Like I said earlier this is a simple golang web app, that serves a html template with GeoIP information.</description></item><item><title>CosmosDB With Serverless app</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/cosmosdb-with-serverless-app/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 20:51:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/cosmosdb-with-serverless-app/</guid><description>Before you contiune further I will just stop you a second. I recomend you read truough my other blog post about Serverless functions with Jenkins. I will skip over the main focus things with did there, to save your time.
We will create a simple serverless REST API that&amp;rsquo;s shows releases for an application. The app is written in .NET and will utilize Cosmos DB.
The code! This is fairly simular to the last azure function with did, with python which you can read here.</description></item><item><title>Serverless Functions With Jenkins</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/serverless-functions-with-jenkins/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 20:51:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/serverless-functions-with-jenkins/</guid><description>What is Serverless and FaaS? FaaS or Functions as a service is just a subset of serverless.
Serverless is focused on both compute, messaging, gateways, databases, and of course functions. Instead of setting up your own, message broker and then write a service that listens on it, you could just write a function and deploy it to Azure, IBM, or AWS, etc.
When you are using FaaS you can choose when the function should trigger, if it&amp;rsquo;s on an HTTP request, message, timer, etc.</description></item><item><title>Docker Build Ci</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/docker-build-ci/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 19:39:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/docker-build-ci/</guid><description>Currently the industry is moving towards containerization and orchestration more. Which has it pros and cons which we wont cover today. But today we will cover how to automate your image build process with Jenkins, and push it to Docker Hub.
You can either use your own docker image, or use this example repo, which is a simple Go web application that writes out the container ip address to the user.</description></item><item><title>What Is Continuous Integration?</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/what-is-continuous-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 10:12:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/what-is-continuous-integration/</guid><description>Continuous Integration (CI) is a term you might have heard sometimes, but wonder what it is and how you can use it to automate your workflow. CI is a process of automating code workflows, such as build, and testing.
Why &amp;amp; What? CI is popular for almost any project regardless the size of it. Instead of building or testing your code manually. It can be triggerd on commits to specific branch in your version control.</description></item><item><title>What is the cloud? Is it the right thing for you?</title><link>https://blog.letnh.com/what-is-the-cloud-is-it-the-right-thing-for-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 10:19:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.letnh.com/what-is-the-cloud-is-it-the-right-thing-for-you/</guid><description>The cloud can be many things, and it&amp;rsquo;s a big subject. Cloud is often called &amp;ldquo;someone else&amp;rsquo;s computer&amp;rdquo;, which it is to some extent. But today we will discuss the subject cloud a bit and give you a brother understanding of what it is and what the pros and cons are.
What is the cloud? You might think that the cloud is just one server that someone owns, which isn&amp;rsquo;t true.</description></item></channel></rss>